Adventure Is Waiting
Zathura: A Space Adventure is a science fiction,
adventure, family film directed by Jon Favreau.
After their father is called into work, two young boys, Walter and Danny, are left in
the care of their teenage sister, Lisa, and told they must stay inside.
Walter and Danny, who anticipate a boring day, are shocked when they begin playing Zathura, a space-themed
board game, which they realize has mystical powers when their house is shot into space.
With the help of an astronaut, the boys attempt to return home.
Walter Budwing, played by Josh Hutcherson.
Danny Budwing, played by Jonah Bobo.
Astronaut, played by Dax Shepard.
Lisa Budwing, played by Kristen Stewart.
Dad (Mr. Budwing), played by Tim Robbins.
Robot (voice), played by Frank Oz.
Zathura: A Space Adventure (or simply Zathura) is a 2005 American science fiction
action-adventure film directed by Jon Favreau and written by David Koepp and John Kamps.
It is an adaptation of the 2002 children's book Zathura by Chris Van
Allsburg, author of the 1981 children's book Jumanji.
It is a standalone spin-off of the 1995 film Jumanji and the
second installment of the Jumanji franchise.
The film stars Josh Hutcherson and Jonah Bobo as two squabbling brothers who find a mysterious board game in the basement
which transports their house into outer space, and must survive and finish the game in order to return home.
Dax Shepard, Kristen Stewart, and Tim Robbins are also among the cast.
Zathura was shot in Los Angeles and Culver City, California, and was released on
November 11, 2005, in the United States by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed $65.1
million worldwide against a $65 million budget.
The film explores themes of fire, based on novel or
book, killer robot, house, space travel.
The tone is thought_provoking.